Oliver Bell

github.com/freshollie · obell.dev

A British computer programmer with 3 years of industry experience and a First Class BSc (Hons) in Computer Science. Specialises in full-stack software engineering. Expertise in designing and writing, tested, maintainable, and distributed software in many languages.

Employment

Bulb Energy LTD, London, UK

Software Engineer III (November 2020 - Present)

• Working on the Smart Meters team developing tools and backend service for smart meter data

YOOX Net-a-Porter Group, London, UK

Software Engineer (May 2019 - November 2020)

- Worked on a team developing internal apps with full-stack JavaScript/TypeScript
- Specialised in writing functional React, using styled-components, GraphQL for local state and network, and graphql-codegen to enforce types between front and backend.
- Followed TDD using react-testing-library and jest, with BDD end to end tests
- Pushed for and implemented a monorepo based architecture for the team

Alelion Energy Systems GmbH, Munich, Germany

Software Engineer (August 2017 - September 2018)

- Developed HA software for their distributed energy storage platform
- Worked with Docker, Python, TypeScript, C++, and Java
- Wrote their main time-series API which used Scylla (cassandra) for a data backend
- Designed and wrote an orchestrator for dynamic service deployment to a docker swarm
- Worked as lead in a small team to re-write their main "Control-Center" UI in Angular 6
- Designed and implemented many microservices to split-up their UI backend

IndiCater Software LTD, Henley-On-Thames, UK

Intern Software Developer (July 2014 - August 2014) (July 2015 - September 2015)

- Developed web-based software used for the management of back-of-house catering
- Wrote server-side VBscript, and frontend javascript

Tech



Interests

- Programming (since 2012)
- FPV Miniquad Racing
- Reverse engineering
- Free Software
- DevOps
- Skiing
- Film-making
- Electronics

Part-time

- McDonalds (2013-2017)
- Compass (2016-2017)
- Delaware North (2018-2019)

Libraries

- jest-dynalite
- abridge
- shuttle-xpress-android
- DisplayDriver

Education

First class BSc (Hons) Computer Science (Coventry University) 2015 - 2019

Computing A Level (B) Computing GCSE (A) Maths A Level (C) Maths GCSE (A*)

Projects

Betaflight Configurator - github.com/freshollie/fresh-configurator

I am in the process of writing an application to configure drone flight controllers over USB. This required writing; a parser to communicate with the flight controller, an api to decode and encode data for the flight controller, a server to provide the data as a GraphQL interface, and an Electron application written in React. All written with TypeScript for full type coverage. The project is structured as a monorepo, and the generic parts of the application are available on NPM: npm.im/org/betaflight

ThatTikTok.Video - thattiktok.video/

That Tiktok Video is an online video curation service which allows users to add TikTok videos which they want to be able to search. The site was built in Next.JS with TypeScript and GraphQL, and is designed with SEO optimisation in mind. The app is a work in progress, but I hope to add more features as time goes on. The current state is proof of concept.